Now, it's time to finish creating our new view
by drawing its contents. And, we do that within our
Custom View's onDraw method. Now, the Android Canvas is pretty
standard as far as canvas API's go. It uses the
Painter's algorithm, meaning that each new thing you paint
will cover anything beneath it. The Canvas and Paint classes
offer a variety of brushes and helpers to draw and
fill lines, boxes, circles, and text with colors, patterns, gradients,
and images, as well as offering the ability to move, rotate,
and scale the canvas while you draw. I could spend a lot
of time here detailing exactly how to use each of these tools,
but there's nothing unique to Android and it's covered really well on
the documentation link below. It is possible though to create pretty advanced
UIs this way. For example, for example, if we start by drawing
a circle and then add a second circle and then you just
need to finish drawing the rest of the compass. Here's an example
I prepared earlier. The specifics of what you draw are
different for every view, but one thing that is consistent
is the resource constraint device you're drawing on. And that
the onDraw method be called every time the screen is
refreshed, potentially many times a second; that means any object
created here within your onDraw method, including things like paint
objects, will be created and destroyed at an alarming frequency.
Object creation and destruction can be expensive on Android; potentially
effecting the smoothness of your UI, when garbage collection is initiated.
The solution? Move the scope of any object used within the
onDraw loop, into the class scope. Go ahead and override the
onDraw method within your new view and draw the new control.
In fact, why not take this opportunity to create a custom
control that can display the wind speed and direction fused within
sunshine. Once you're done, you can add it to your layer
using it it's full package name and class name in the XML
like this. Run it and then post a screenshot of your new view into the forum.